Nicolas Chang

Senior React Engineer

(Javascript | React | Node | Typescript | GraphQL | AWS)

Contact

Phone +16264673805

Address
1340 Pasqualito Dr |
San Marino | CA | 91108

Email nicolaschang199@gmail.com

Skill set

React

MongoDB

Next

Postgresql

Gatsby

Graphql

Redux

Solidity

Jest

Web3.js

Node

AWS Azure

Express

Git

Laravel

Dokcer

Mysql

WebSocket

Language

English / Korean / Chinese

About Me

A Senior React Engineer who has been working as a professional web developer more than 10 years, most proficient at frontend development using React and Javascript.

Always produced and built **optimized**, **user friendly** web pages with great performance and rich user experience using **React**, **Next**, **Angular and Typescript**. I from time to time got involved in **full stack developer** roles and once was in responsible of some kind of **leadership** as well.

Using **MERN** stack, I have done some kind of small projects totally by myself. That surely improved my backend and full-stack development skills and experience.

My skills in terms of backend and full stack development would be **Javascript**, **Node**, **GraphQL**, **MongoDB**, **MySQL**, **PHP** and **PHP** frameworks like Laravel or Wordpress.

In addition, I have some relevant experience in **smart contract** development using **Solidity** when it comes to the **blockchain technology** such as **Defi**, **NFT** and something like that.

However, my mainly work is still focused on **frontend development** particularly using React and Javascript.

In conclusion, my strongest skills are Javascript / React / Node / Typescript / GraphQL / AWS.

I can afford any sort of web developer or engineer roles on demand.

Education

2008 - 2012

Jiang Xi University of Science & Technology

- Was a member of a basket ball team
- Specialty was the computer science
- Bachelor's degree
- Studied web development and walked through online courses

Courses & Trainings

- Web Design for Everybody Specialization Course
 University of Michigan (Online course)
- Front-End Web Developer Learning Path Lynda.com
- Web Developer Bootcamp

 Udemy.com
- The Complete Javascript Course

 Udemv.com
- GraphQL with React: The Complete Developers Guide Udemy.com

Work Experiences

Sr React Engineer at Velog, Seoul (Remote)

Jan 2020 - Mar 2022

- Developed new user-facing features using React.js
- Built reusable components and front-end libraries for future use
- Translated designs and wireframes into high quality
- Optimized components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers
- Worked together with an engineering team, a designer and a project manager to achieve the goals of the application
- Estimate tasks accordingly based on your past experience
- Provide help and guidance to other engineers on the project
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance

Software Engineer at CoreLogic, Los Angeles

Jun 2013 - Oct 2014

- Developed high-quality software design and architecture
- Identified, prioritized, and executed tasks in the software development life cycle
- Developed tools and applications by producing clean,
 efficient code
- Automated tasks through appropriate tools and scripting
- Reviewed and debug code
- Performed validation and verification testing
- Collaborated with internal teams and vendors to fix and improve products
- Documented development phases and monitor systems
- Ensured software is up-to-date with the latest technologies

Sr Front-End Software Engineer at TopicPro, Chicago

Nov 2014 - Dec 2019

- Did plan, design, build, and implement the user interface systems of websites, software programs, and web-based applications
- Provided a satisfactory user experience with no issues, errors, or downtime
- Created and Optimized systems, played an active role in testing and troubleshooting, and resolved issues such as those related to accessibility and browser compatibility
- Often served as an intermediary bridging the gap between the user and the backend developers, and tweak tools and platforms to adapt to real-world use situations
- Reviewed and debugged code
- Developed fully functional web applications that align with business objectives.
- Followed the best practices in developments and improved them
- Created high resolution **mockups** to **test interfaces** with users.

Full Stack Developer at Rikkeisoft, Tokyo (Remote)

May 2012 - Jun 2013

- Developed front end website architecture.
- Developed **back-end** website applications.
- Created servers and databases for functionality.
- Ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones.
- Ensuring **responsiveness** of applications.
- Working alongside graphic designers for web design features.
- Seeing through a project from conception to finished product.
- Designing and developing APIs.
- Meeting both technical and consumer needs.
- Staying abreast of developments in web applications and programming languages.

Typical projects

https://bondlingo.tv/

BondLingo is an online platform that offers more than 500 lecture videos and hundreds of JLPT problems to assist people to learn Japanese. It also provides features for users to feel free to create their own problem sets or movies.

The client requested us to establish a platform where people can acquire the Japanese language. The integrated Mobile App needs to enhance creativity and make teachers gain self-confidence in creating and distributing every lesson plan.

To suit the client's requirements, our team of 9 developers built a web-based solution and mobile app utilizing some technologies such as NodeJS, WordPress, and ReactJS.

I took part in this project as a React JS developer.

TECHNOLOGY STACK:

- Node.js
- React
- HTML / SCSS
- Wordpress

https://apkpure.com/lolly-chat-with-idols-old/com.myfans

Lolly Idol Chat app connects teenagers with their favorite youth celebrity and enables 1 on 1 chat.

Interactive portal for social media influencers and their fans. Fans can send virtual gifts, chat and exchange snap moments with their favorite Instagram idols. There is a leaderboard to show who is your most popular idols and your top fans. Accumulate enough virtual gifts to redeem for cash.

I was in response to developing software solutions by studying information needs, conferring with users, studying and designing systems flow, data

I made the documents and demonstrated solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, code comments, and clear code. Sometimes, I had to update my job by studying programming techniques and computing equipment, participating in educational opportunities, reading professional publications and etc.

Our team developed the following features based on customer requests:

The user gets updated with their favorite idols and influencers private snaps

User can show their appreciation by sending virtual gifts

Grow fan base, keep the followers engaged by showing interesting offers

TECHNOLOGY STACK

- React-native
- PHP
- jQuery
- MongoDB
- Redis
- SOOL
- AWS EC2
- AWS S3

https://www.powerlook.in/

Powerlook is one of the fastest-growing e-commerce brands in India which offers a unique range of men's casual wear with a shade of western touch. Powerlook is a family-owned business that started its first retail shop in 2010.

They have three retail shops in Andheri.

Borivali and Thane in Mumbai.

In this project, I was in charge of frontend development using React and Emotion.

TECHNOLOGY STACK

- React
- Emotion
- Webpack
- Bootstrap